Donald T. Regan Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Treasury Department, 1975-1992 (Box 1-188)
  - Subject File, 1975-1992 (Box 99-188)
    - Exports
      - Credit, 1983
      - Export Administration Act, 1983
      - President's Export Council, 1981-1982, (3 folders)
    - Falkland Islands, 1982 (Box 144)
    - Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), 1980-1983
    - Federal Financing Bank, 1981-1982
    - Federal Reserve Board
      - Biographical material, 1982-1983, undated
      - Clippings, 1981-1982
      - General
        - Jan. 1981-Feb. 1982, (4 folders)
        - Mar. 1982-July 1983, (6 folders) (Box 145)
        - Aug. 1983-Jan. 1985, (7 folders) (Box 146)
    - Federalism, 1981-1983, (3 folders) (Box 147)
    - Financial Corp. of America, 1984
    - Financial deregulation See also Containers 103-104, Banking
      - Depository Institutions Deregulation Committee
        - Apr. 1980-Sept. 1982, (4 folders)
        - Oct. 1982-Sept. 1984, (3 folders) (Box 148)
      - Miscellany, 1981-1983, (3 folders)
      - Vice President's Task Group on Regulation of Financial Services, 1983-1984, undated
    - Financing, 1981-1982
    - Foreign exchange, 1982-1983, undated
    - Fowler-McCracken Commission, 1981 (Box 149)
    - France, 1982-1983
    - Germany, 1982-1983
    - Gifts, 1981-1983, (2 folders)
    - Gold
      - General, 1981-1983, (2 folders)
      - Gold Commission
        - Apr.-July 1981, (2 folders)
        - Aug. 1981-Mar. 1982, (7 folders) (Box 150)
    - Grace Commission, 1982-1984
    - Group of Five (G-5) meetings, 1979-1983 (Box 151)
    - Group of Ten (G-10) meetings, 1982-1984
    - Housing, 1981-1982, (2 folders)
    - Inaugural functions, 1980-1981
    - Individual retirement accounts, 1983
    - Inflation, 1980-1981
    - Interest rates, 1982-1983
    - Internal Revenue Service
      - Apr. 1981-Feb.1982, (3 folders)
      - Mar. 1982-Jan. 1985, undated, (5 folders) (Box 152)
    - International debt, 1983-1984
    - International financial institutions, 1981
    - International Monetary Fund (IMF)
      - Briefing books, 1983, (2 folders); (8 folders) (Box 153)
      - General, 1981-1984, undated, (5 folders) (Box 154)
      - Interim Committee, 1981-1984
      - International Monetary Fund-World Bank meetings, 1981-1982, (3 folders)
    - Iran, 1981-1982 (Box 155)
    - Israel, 1982-1984 See also same container, Joint commissions and committees
    - Jamaica, 1984
    - Japan, 1983-1985, (5 folders)
    - Joint commissions and committees
      - United States-China Joint Economic Committee, 1981-1983 See also Container 131, China
      - United States-Israel Joint Committee for Investment and Trade, 1978 See also same container, Israel
      - United States-Saudi Arabian Joint Commission on Economic Cooperation, 1981-1983 See also Container 166, Saudi Arabia, (2 folders) (Box 156)
      - United States-USSR Commercial Commission See also Container 171, Soviet Union
    - Korean airline incident, 1983
    - Legislative agenda, 1980-1985
    - Metropolitan Transit Authority of New York, N.Y., 1982
    - Mexico, 1981-1984
    - Miscellaneous material
      - 1980-1981, (2 folders)
      - 1982-1984, undated, (3 folders) (Box 157)
    - Monetary policy, 1981-1985, (4 folders)
    - Multilateral development banks, 1981-1984, (2 folders)
    - National narcotics border interdiction system, 1984 (Box 158)
    - New York, N.Y., 1981-1982
    - Nomination and confirmation as secretary of the treasury, 1980-1981, undated, (7 folders); (3 folders) (Box 159)
    - Notes, 1981-1985, undated, (6 folders)
    - Objectives, 1981-1982, (2 folders)
    - Office of Management and Budget, 1981-1984, (5 folders) (Box 160)
    - Oil, 1981-1984, (2 folders)
    - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), 1982-1983 (Box 161)
    - Pan American World Airways, 1981
    - Penn Square Bank, Oklahoma City, Okla., 1982
    - Pension Benefit Guarantee Corp., 1981-1984, (3 folders)
    - Personal miscellany, 1981-1984, undated
    - Personnel, 1978-1984, undated, (3 folders) (Box 162)
    - Peru, 1984
    - Philippines, 1983-1984, undated
    - Poland, 1983-1984
    - Political events, 1981-1982
    - President's Economic Policy Advisory Board
      - 1981-1982, (3 folders)
      - 1983-1984, (2 folders) (Box 163)
    - President's Task Force on Immigration and Refugee Policy, 1981, (2 folders)
    - Press, 1980-1985, (4 folders) (Box 164)
    - Productivity, 1981-1982, (3 folders)
    - Quadriad breakfast, 1983
    - Quarterly refunding, 1982-1983
    - Rampart project, undated
    - Regulatory reform, 1981-1983, undated (Box 165)
    - Representation fund, 1984
    - Resignation letters, 1982-1984
    - Revenue raisers, 1981, undated, (5 folders); (1 folder) (Box 166)
    - Revenue sharing, 1981-1984, (2 folders)
    - Roberts, Craig, 1981-1984
    - Saudi Arabia, 1981-1982 See also Container 156, Joint commissions and committees
    - Savings and loan associations See Containers 147-148, Financial deregulation, and Containers 179-182, Thrift industry
    - Savings bonds, 1979-1984, (4 folders)
    - Schedule proposals (Box 167)
      - Jan. 1981-Dec. 1982, (7 folders)
      - Jan. 1983-July 1984, (7 folders) (Box 168)
      - Aug.-Dec. 1984, (2 folders) (Box 169)
    - Secret Service, 1981-1984, (5 folders)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission, 1981-1984
    - Senior Interagency Group on International Economic Policy, 1982-1983, (2 folders) (Box 170)
    - Social security
      - Feb. 1981-Aug. 1982, (5 folders)
      - Sept. 1982-July 1984, (6 folders) (Box 171)
    - Soviet Union, 1983 See also Container 156, Joint commissions and committees
    - Speech material, 1983-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 172)
    - Staff meeting notes
      - Jan. 1981-July 1984, (5 folders)
      - Aug.-Dec. 1984 (Box 173)
    - State Department, 1982-1983
    - State of the union address, 1982-1984, (3 folders)
    - Steel, 1984
    - Tax
      - Analysis, 1981-1983, undated
      - Contingency tax, 1983
      - Flat-rate tax, 1982-1984, 1992
      - Foreign tax credit, 1981
      - General
        - 1981, (2 folders)
        - 1982-1984, undated, (4 folders) (Box 174)
      - Legislation, 1980-1984, undated, (3 folders); (7 folders); (2 folders) (Box 175, Box 176, Box 177)
      - Reform, 1984-1985, undated, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 178)
      - Tuition tax credit, 1982-1983
      - Unitary taxation, 1983-1984, (4 folders)
      - Withholding on interest and dividends, 1982-1983, (2 folders)
    - Telephone logs, 1981-1985, (2 folders)
    - Textiles, 1984 (Box 179)
    - Thank-you letters, 1981-1984, (6 folders)
    - Thrift industry
      - General, 1981-1982, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 180)
      - Savings and loan industry investigation, 1981-1991, undated, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 181, Box 182)
    - Timber industry, 1983-1984
    - Trade organization group, 1983
    - Trade Policy Committee, 1980-1983, (2 folders)
    - Transition
      - Briefing material, 1980-1981, undated, (1 folder); (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 183, Box 184)
      - Economics, 1980-1981, undated
      - Miscellaneous material, 1977-1981, undated, (2 folders)
      - Schedules, 1980-1981 (Box 185)
      - Task Force on Tax Policy, 1979-1980, (3 folders)
    - United Kingdom, 1981-1985
    - United States Mint, 1981-1984, (3 folders)
    - United States Synthetic Fuels Corp., 1981 (Box 186)
    - United States trade representative, 1981-1984
    - VAX computer, 1983
    - Venezuela, 1983-1984
    - White House
      - Core group meetings, 1984
      - General
        - Dec. 1980-Feb. 1983, (5 folders)
        - Mar. 1983-Jan. 1985, (5 folders) (Box 187)
      - Meetings with the president, 1982
      - Vice president, 1981-1982 For additional material see Container 148, Financial deregulation
    - Wirthlin, Richard, polls
      - Feb.-Sept. 1981, (2 folders)
      - Oct. 1981-Nov. 1984, (5 folders) (Box 188)
    - World Bank, 1981-1984 For additional material see Container 154, International Monetary Fund, (2 folders)
    - Yugoslavia, 1983
- White House, 1947-1993 (Box 189-216)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, schedules, telephone logs, speeches, invitations, transcripts, clippings, reports, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or topic and chronologically therein.
  - Correspondence, 1985-1987, undated, (4 folders) (Box 189)
  - Invitations, 1985-1986, (3 folders)
  - Notes
    - Daily meetings
      - Feb.-Mar. 1985
      - Apr.-Nov. 1985, (7 folders) (Box 190)
      - Dec. 1985-May 1986, (6 folders) (Box 191)
      - June-Oct. 1986, (9 folders) (Box 192)
      - Mar. 1985-Dec. 1986, Jan. 1992 (Box 193)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Press
    - Clippings
      - Albums
        - Feb.-Apr. 1985, (7 folders)
        - May-July 1985, (9 folders) (Box 194)
        - Aug.-Dec. 1985, (11 folders) (Box 195)
        - Jan.-May 1986, (10 folders) (Box 196)
        - June-Oct. 1986, (9 folders) (Box 197)
        - Nov. 1986-Jan. 1987, (12 folders) (Box 198)
        - Feb.-Mar. 1987, (7 folders) (Box 199)
      - Miscellaneous, 1985-1987, (3 folders) (Box 200)
    - Transcripts, 1986-1987, (3 folders)
  - Schedules
    - Feb.-Sept. 1985, (4 folders)
    - Oct. 1985-Sept. 1986, (9 folders) (Box 201)
    - Oct. 1986-Feb. 1987, (5 folders) (Box 202)
  - Speeches
    - Mar.-May 1985, (2 folders)
    - June 1985-June 1986, (6 folders) (Box 203)
    - July-Dec. 1986, (7 folders) (Box 204)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1987, (2 folders) (Box 205)
  - Subject File
    - Iran-Contra affair
      - Briefing book, undated, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 206)
      - Investigations
        - Congress, 1986-1988, undated, (5 folders); (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 207, Box 208)
        - Independent counsel, 1986-1993, undated, (6 folders); (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 209, Box 210)
        - President's Special Review Board (Tower Board), 1986-1987, (3 folders) (Box 211)
      - Miscellany, 1985-1991, undated, (2 folders)
      - Presidential addresses and remarks, 1947, 1985-1987
      - Press, 1986-1987, undated, (1 folder); (7 folders) (Box 212)
      - Printed matter, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 213)
      - Schedules and telephone logs, 1986
      - United States v. Evans, et al., 1988
      - United States v. North, 1988-1989
      - United States v. Poindexter, 1990
    - Libya, 1986
    - Miscellany, 1985-1987, undated, (2 folders)
    - Planning, 1985-1987
    - Presidential appointments, 1985-1987
    - Reagan, Ronald, medical treatments, 1985-1987 For additional material see Container 230, Research (Box 214)
    - Resignation, 1987, (5 folders)
    - Revenge, 1986-1989, (2 folders)
    - Soviet Union, 1985-1987 See also Container 215, Summit meetings, (2 folders)
    - State of the union address, 1987 (Box 215)
    - Summit meetings See also Container 214, Soviet Union
      - Bonn, West Germany, 1985
      - Geneva, Switzerland, 1985, undated For additional material see Container 229, Research, (2 folders)
      - Reykjavik, Iceland, 1985-1987, (3 folders)
      - Tokyo, Japan, 1986
    - Transition, 1985, (2 folders)
    - United States v. Deaver, 1985-1989, (2 folders)
  - Telephone logs, 1985-1987, (8 folders) (Box 216)
- Personal File, 1919-1993 (Box 217-242)
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, speeches, book manuscripts and related material, writings, transcripts, and other material covering Regan's activities outside government service.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or activity and chronologically therein.
  - Correspondence (Box 217)
    - 1987-1988, (6 folders)
    - 1989-1991, (6 folders) (Box 218)
  - Economic subject matter, 1988-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 219)
  - Family material, 1968, 1976-1979, 1988
  - Merrill Lynch and Co., 1946-1982, (6 folders)
  - Miscellaneous engagements, 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 220)
  - Notes, 1988-1993
  - Organizations and committees
    - Advisory Council on Japan-U.S. Economic Relations, 1974-1975
    - Belle Haven Country Club, Alexandria, Va., 1979
    - Burning Tree Club, Washington, D.C., 1971-1982, undated
    - Business Hall of Fame, 1980, undated
    - Charles E. Merrill Trust, 1961, 1980-1984
    - Coalition for New York, 1978-1980, undated
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., business gifts committee, 1980
    - Metropolitan Club, Washington, D.C., 1978-1980
    - Professional Golfers' Association of America, tournament policy board, 1968-1981, undated, (2 folders)
    - Securities Investor Protection Corp., 1971 (Box 221)
    - Skytop Club, Skytop, Pa., 1974-1983, undated
    - Topeka Club, New York, N.Y., 1979-1980
    - United States Marine Corps, 1966-1980, (2 folders)
    - University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pa.
      - Board of trustees, 1970-1981, undated, (2 folders)
      - Donald T. Regan Professorship in English, 1981-1982
      - Miscellaneous material, 1973-1981, undated, (2 folders)
    - Winthrop H. Smith Trusts, 1961, 1980-1982
  - Political activities (Box 222)
    - Contributions and contacts, 1964-1980, (3 folders)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., fund-raiser, 1976-1977
    - Reagan, Ronald, campaign, 1980, (4 folders)
    - Republican Senatorial Trust, 1980-1981
    - Victory '72 dinner committee, 1972
    - Washington, D.C., 1968-1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box 223)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Books
      - "The Changing Market Place" (unpublished), 1977, undated, (4 folders)
      - For the Record (Box 224)
        - Correspondence, 1988-1990, (6 folders)
        - Illustrations, 1981-1988, undated
        - Malcontents, 1987-1990, undated, (3 folders) (Box 225)
        - Manuscripts of text, 1987-1992, undated, (7 folders) (Box 226, Box 227)
        - McCarry, Charles, 1987-1988, undated, (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1987-1988, undated (Box 228)
        - Paperback edition, 1988-1989, (2 folders)
        - Press clippings, 1987-1989, undated, (2 folders)
        - Proceeds, charitable requests, 1988
        - Publicity, 1986-1989, undated, (4 folders)
        - Research, 1919, 1948-1958, 1971-1992, undated, (10 folders); (5 folders) (Box 229, Box 230)
        - Transcripts, 1987, (8 folders); (14 folders); (13 folders) (Box 231, Box 232, Box 233)
      - A View From the Street, audiocassettes, 1970 transferred to Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division
    - Commentaries (Box 234)
      - NBC News
        - "Before Hours," 1987-1988, (6 folders)
        - "News at Sunrise," 1988-1989, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 235)
      - NBC Radio Network, 1987-1988, undated, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 236)
    - Editorials, 1987-1989, undated
    - Speeches
      - Apr.-July 1987, (5 folders)
      - Aug. 1987-Jan. 1988, (8 folders) (Box 237)
      - Feb.-June 1988, (6 folders) (Box 238)
      - Sept. 1988-May 1989, (7 folders) (Box 239)
      - Sept. 1989-Oct. 1990, (6 folders) (Box 240)
      - Feb. 1991-Sept. 1992, (5 folders) (Box 241)
    - Statements and speeches supporting supply-side economics, 1969-1980, (2 folders)
    - Testimony, 1988-1991 For additional material see Containers 180-182, Thrift industry; and Containers 205-213, Iran-Contra Affair, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 242)
    - Writing projects, 1988-1990, undated, (4 folders)
  - Television appearances, 1987-1990 For additional material see Containers 234-235, NBC News, (2 folders)
- Classified, 1979-1987 (Box CL 1-CL 4)
  Government security classified correspondence, memoranda, reports, and notes.
  Described according to the series, folders, and boxes from which the items were removed.
  - Treasury Department (Box CL 1)
    - Chronological Files
      - Official, 1982-1984 (Containers 10-20)
      - Reading and information, 1983-1984 (Containers 25-27)
      - Staff notes, 1984 (Containers 27-28)
    - Correspondence
      - A, 1982 (Container 29)
    - Memoranda
      - Business and consumer affairs, 1984 (Container 37)
      - Chew, David L., 1983 (Container 38)
      - Deputy secretary, 1984 (Container 38)
      - Domestic finance, 1984 (Containers 40-41)
      - Economic policy, 1983 (Container 43)
      - Enforcement and operations, 1984 (Containers 46-47)
      - General counsel, 1982-1984 (Containers 49-50)
      - International affairs
        - Apr. 1981-Mar. 1984, (6 folders) (Containers 50-51)
        - Apr. 1984, (6 folders) (Container 51) (Box CL 2)
      - Legislative affairs, 1983 (Container 52)
      - Monetary affairs, 1983 (Container 56)
      - Porter, Roger B., 1984 (Container 57)
      - Staff, 1984 (Container 59)
      - Tax policy, 1981-1984 (Containers 60-62)
      - White House
        - Reagan, Ronald
          - Outgoing, 1983 (Container 65)
    - Speech and Engagement File
      - General, 1981-1983 (Containers 81, 93-94)
    - Subject File (Box CL 3)
      - Acting secretaries, correspondence signed
        - McNamar, Richard T., 1982-1983 (Container 99)
        - Sprinkel, Beryl W., 1983-1984 (Container 99)
      - Advisory Committee on International Monetary System (Fowler Committee), 1984 (Container 100)
      - Appointments and schedules
        - Daily log, 1982 (Container 100)
      - Automobile industry
        - Automobile Industry Task Force, 1981, (2 folders) (Container 103)
      - Brazil, 1982-1983 (Container 104)
      - Budget
        - Fiscal year
          - 1985
            - Budget review board, 1984 (Container 110)
          - 1986
            - Briefing book, 1984 (Container 112)
      - Cabinet councils
        - Commerce and trade, 1982-1984, (2 folders) (Containers 116-117)
        - Economic affairs, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Containers 118-120)
      - Canada, 1984 (Container 130)
      - Council of Economic Advisors, 1983 (Container 135)
      - Customs, 1982 (Container 136)
      - Debt ceiling, 1982-1983 (Container 136)
      - Development Committee, 1984 (Container 137)
      - Economic situation, 1983, (2 folders) (Container 139)
      - Economic summits
        - Cancun, Mexico, 1981 (Container 140)
        - Ottawa, Canada, 1981 (Container 141)
        - Williamsburg, Va., 1982 (Container 142)
      - Exports
        - Export Administration Act, 1983 (Container 143)
      - Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), 1981-1982 (Container 144)
      - Federal Reserve Board, 1983 (Container 145)
      - France, 1983 (Container 149)
      - Germany, 1983 (Container 149)
      - Group of Five (G-5) meetings, 1979-1983 (Container 151)
      - Group of Ten (G-10) meetings, 1983-1984 (Container 151)
      - International Monetary Fund (IMF) (Box CL 4)
        - Interim Committee, 1981 (Container 154)
      - Israel, 1982 (Container 155)
      - Jamaica, 1984 (Container 155)
      - Japan, 1984 (Container 155)
      - Korean airline incident, 1983 (Container 156)
      - Notes, 1984 (Container 159)
      - Objectives, 1981 (Container 159)
      - Oil, 1983 (Container 160)
      - Poland, 1983 (Container 162)
      - Quadriad breakfast, 1983 (Container 164)
      - Saudi Arabia, 1981-1982 (Container 166)
      - Schedule proposals, 1981-1982 (Container 167)
      - Senior Interagency Group on International Economic Policy, 1982-1983 (Container 170)
      - State Department, 1983 (Container 173)
      - Tax
        - Unitary taxation, 1983-1984 (Container 178)
      - Trade Policy Committee, 1983 (Container 182)
      - United Kingdom, 1981-1985 (Container 185)
      - United States trade representative, 1981 (Container 186)
      - White House
        - General, 1983 (Container 187)
      - World Bank, 1982 (Container 188)
  - White House
    - Notes
      - Daily meetings, 1985-1986 (Containers 189, 191)
    - Subject File
      - Iran-Contra Affair
        - Investigations
          - Congress, 1986 (Container 206)
      - Miscellaneous material, 1985-1987 (Container 211)
      - Soviet Union, 1986 (Container 214)
      - Summit meetings
        - Reykjavik, Iceland, 1986 (Container 215)
      - Transition, 1985 (Container 215)
  - Personal File
    - Speeches and writings
      - Books
        - For the Record
          - Research, 1984 (Container 229)
- Top Secret, 1987 (Box TS 1)
  Top secret government security classified congressional hearing transcript.
  Described according to the series, folder, and box from which it was removed.
  - White House (Box TS 1)
    - Subject File
      - Iran-Contra Affair
        - Investigations
          - Congress, 1986 (Container 206)